101 College Street, PMCRT 11-410 • Toronto, ON M5G 1L7 (416) 879-6775 • Heewon.Seo@lootpiz.com

### SUMMARY

Skilled bioinformatician in biomedical science with experience analyzing thousands of wholegenomes, exomes, and transcriptomes to discover molecular biomarkers for precision therapeutics and novel synergistic drug combinations for determining best treatment strategies via advanced statistical analysis and predictive modelling methods.

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Development of new tools and advanced statistical models for biomedical big data analysis
- Rapid construction of complex computational pipelines and their optimization
- Experience in working in high performance computing environments (on-premise and cloud)

### **EDUCATION**

### PhD in Medical Science (Biomedical Informatics)

Sep 2012 - Feb 2018

Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea

Thesis: Methods for Variant- and Gene-based Analysis for Pharmacogenomics Research.

### **MS** in **Medicine** (Biomedical Informatics)

Sep 2010 - Aug 2012

Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea

Thesis: Loss of Function Gene-set Analysis of Personal Genome using Pathway-disease Similarity.

### **BS in Computer Science**

Mar 2004 - Feb 2010

Sejong University, Seoul, Korea

GPA: 4.37/4.5, Summa Cum Laude, achieved the early graduation of excellent students within 3 years

### RESEARCH/WORK EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Fellow Jan 2018 - Present

Princess Margaret Cancer Centre, University Health Network, Toronto, Canada

- Developed the largest integrated database in high-throughput drug combination studies, SYNERGxDB (http://SYNERGxDB.ca/), and integrated high-dimensional molecular profiles of the corresponding preclinical models
- Discovered two synergistic drug combinations and four meaningful expression-based biomarkers via statistical analysis in personalized medicine
- Built predictive models using several machine learning algorithms of cancer treatment response using transcriptomic data
- Created a semi-automatic analysis tool on Microsoft Azure using Jupyter Notebook for exploring large pharmacogenomics datasets
- Built a translational framework for precision cancer medicine using a compendium of preclinical multimodal pharmacogenomics datasets and large clinical patients cohorts
- Devised an online tool to report significant biomarkers using a semi-automation system for better data representation and easier data investigation with multiple levels of granularity

101 College Street, PMCRT 11-410 • Toronto, ON M5G 1L7 (416) 879-6775 • Heewon.Seo@lootpiz.com

## RESEARCH/WORK EXPERIENCE (Cont'd)

- Performed meta-analysis of pancreatic cancer cell lines to discover expression-based biomarkers
  predictive of drug responses in order to improve current treatment strategies
- Analyzed multiple preclinical models including patient-derived cell lines and organoids in single or pairwise drug testing and their molecular profiles (feature space exceeding 50K)
- Identified two promising drug resistance biomarkers that may help patients overcome drug resistance in combination with inhibitors in pancreatic cancer

## **Visiting Researcher**

Jan 2018 - Present

Ontario Institute for Cancer Research (OICR), Toronto, Canada

- Analyzed large scale genomic and clinical data with appropriate statistical methods in order to identify gemcitabine resistance biomarkers in pancreatic cancer cohorts
- Discovered gemcitabine resistance biomarkers to select drugs (i.e., inhibitors) that sensitize gemcitabine resistance in pancreatic cancer and validated in patient-derived organoids
- Conducted survival meta-analysis to validate the biomarkers in multiple pancreatic cancer cohorts to improve patient outcomes
- Participated in the molecular tumour board of the COMPASS (Changes and Characteristics of Genes in Patients With Pancreatic Cancer for Better Treatment Selection) trial

### **Doctoral Researcher**

Sep 2012 - Dec 2017

Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea

- Successfully found pharmaco-genes and -variants that have an association with mercaptopurineinduced neutropenia or busulfan-induced hepatotoxicity in paediatric cancer patients and ritodrine-induced pulmonary oedema in pregnant women
- Identified favourable prognostic markers of survival in allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation patients in donor exomes
- Solely developed a pharmacogenomics analysis platform for the analysis and interpretation of patient genomes and exomes in order to identify drug side effect associated genes and variants
- Built a computational gene-level approach to aggregate the impact of heterogeneous variants in sequencing data
- Analyzed whole-genome, whole-exome, targeted panels, whole-transcriptome, small RNAs, and microarray data with clinical information across platforms (i.e., Ion Proton, Complete Genomics, and Illumina)
- Localized big open public omics datasets such TCGA (The Cancer Genome Atlas), 1KGP (1000 Genomes Project), ADSP (Alzheimer's Disease Sequencing Project), and SFARI (Simons Foundation Autism Research Initiative)
- Doubled as a Server Administrator who was responsible for setting up and maintaining largescale servers (472 cores, 4.25 TB RAM) and storage (756 TB) in Network/Lustre/Fraunhofer File Systems

101 College Street, PMCRT 11-410 • Toronto, ON M5G 1L7 (416) 879-6775 • Heewon.Seo@lootpiz.com

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- SYNERGxDB: an Integrative Pharmacogenomic Portal to Identify Synergistic Drug Combinations for Precision Oncology. <u>Heewon Seo</u>†, Denis Tkachuk, Chantal Ho, Anthony Mammoliti, Aria Rezaie, Seyed Ali Madani Tonekaboni, and Benjamin Haibe-Kains\* *Nucleic Acids Res* 2020
- Discovery of Donor Genotype Associated with Long-term Survival of Patients with Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation in Refractory Acute Myeloid Leukemia. Chan-Young Ock†, Heewon Seo†, Dae-Yoon Kim, Byung Joo Min, Yoomi Park, Hyun Sub Cheong, Eun-Young Song, Inho Kim, Sung-Soo Yoon, Ju Han Kim\*, and Youngill Koh\* Leuk Lymphoma 2018;60(7):1775-1781
- Deleterious Genetic Variants in Ciliopathy Genes Increase Risk of Ritodrine-induced Cardiac and Pulmonary Side Effects. <u>Heewon Seo</u>†, Eun Jin Kwon†, Young-Ah You, Yoomi Park, Byung Joo Min, Kyunghun Yoo, Han Sung Hwang, Ju Han Kim\*, and Young Ju Kim\* <u>BMC Med Genomics</u> 2018;11(1):4
- APEX1 Polymorphism and Mercaptopurine-related Early Onset Neutropenia in Pediatric
   Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia. Hyery Kim<sup>†</sup>, Heewon Seo<sup>†</sup>, Yoomi Park, Byung Joo Min, Myung Eui Seo,
   Kyung Duk Park, Hee Young Shin, Ju Han Kim<sup>\*</sup>, and Hyoung Jin Kang<sup>\*</sup> Cancer Res Treat 2018;50(3):823-834
- Idiopathic Hypereosinophilia Is Clonal Disorder? Clonality Identified by Targeted Sequencing. Jee-Soo Lee†, Heewon Seo, Kyongok Im, Si Nae Park, Sung-Min Kim, Jung-Ah Kim, Seon Young Kim, Joon-hee Lee, Sunghoon Kwon, Miyoung Kim, Insong Koh, Seungwoo Hwang, Heung-Woo Park, Ju Han Kim, and Dong Soon Lee\* *PLoS One* 2017;12(10):e0185602
- Evaluation of Exome Variants using the Ion Proton Platform to Sequence Error-Prone Regions. Heewon Seo<sup>†</sup>, Yoomi Park<sup>†</sup>, Byung Joo Min, Myung Eui Seo, and Ju Han Kim\* *PLoS One* 2017;12(7):e0181304
- Posttranslational control of T-cell development by the ESCRT protein CHMP5. Stanley Adoro<sup>†</sup>,
   Kwang H Park, Sarah E Bettigole, Raphael Lis, Hee Rae Shin, <u>Heewon Seo</u>, Ju Han Kim, Klaus-Peter Knobeloch,
   Jae-Hyuck Shim\*, Laurie H Glimcher\* *Nat Immunol* 2017;18(7):780-790
- Disease Markers of Pediatric Idiopathic Nephrotic Syndrome and Markers of Steroid-responsiveness: Whole-transcriptome Sequencing of Peripheral Mononuclear Cells. Hee Gyung Kang<sup>†</sup>, Heewon Seo<sup>†</sup>, Jae Hyun Lim, Jong II Kim, Kyoung Hee Han, Hey Won Park, Ja Wook Koo, Kee Hyuck Kim, Ju Han Kim<sup>\*</sup>, Hae II Cheong, and II-Soo Ha<sup>\*</sup> J Int Med Res 2017;45(3):948-963
- Gastrointestinal Tuberculosis is not Associated with Proton Pump Inhibitors: A Retrospective Cohort Study. Kyoung Sup Hong<sup>†</sup>, Seung Joo Kang, Jong Kyoung Choi, Ju Han Kim, <u>Heewon Seo</u>, Suehyun Lee, Jae-Woo Jung, Hye-Ryun Kang, Sang-Heon Cho, and Joo Sung Kim\* *World J Gastroenterol* 2013;19(2):258-264
- Development of Korean Rare Disease Knowledge Base. <u>Heewon Seo</u><sup>†</sup>, Dokyoon Kim, Jong-Hee Chae, Hee Gyung Kang, Buyng Chan Lim, Hae II Cheong, and Ju Han Kim\* *Healthc Inform Res* 2012;18(04):272-278

101 College Street, PMCRT 11-410 • Toronto, ON M5G 1L7 (416) 879-6775 • Heewon.Seo@lootpiz.com

### ABSTRACTS/POSTERS

- Targeting Pancreatic Cancer Organoids with Dual BET and CBP/P300 Inhibitor NEO2734.
   Nikolina Radulovich, Laura Tramblyn, <u>Heewon Seo</u>, Benjamin Haibe-Kains, Mathieu Lupien, Francis Giles, and Ming-Sound Tsao AACR Pancreas 2019
- Pharmacogenomics of Gemcitabine in Pancreatic Cancer Cell Lines. <u>Heewon Seo</u> and Benjamin Haibe-Kains, *BioC* 2018
- Discovery of Donor Genotype Associated with Long-Term Survival of Patients with Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation in Refractory Acute Myeloid Leukemia. Chan-Young Ock, Heewon Seo, Dae-Yoon Kim, Inho Kim, Sung-Soo Yoon, Ju Han Kim and Youngil Koh *Blood* 2017
- Analysis of Genetic Variants Related to the Hepatic Veno-Occlusive Disease in Pediatric Patients Receiving HSCT with Targeted Dose Busulfan Based Conditioning. Jung Yoon Choi, <u>Heewon Seo</u>, Yoomi Park, ByungJoo Min, Hyery Kim, Kyung Taek Hong, Che Ry Hong, Sang Hoon Song, Kyung-Sang Yu, In-Jin Jang, Kyung Duk Park, Hee Young Shin, Ju Han Kim and Hyoung Jin Kang *Blood 2017*
- Staring inside of Idiopathic Hypereosinophilia: Identification of Clonality Using Targeted Exome Sequencing. Jee-Soo Lee, <u>Heewon Seo</u>, Kyongok Im, Si Nae Park, Jung-Ah Kim, Seon Young Kim, Joon-hee Lee, Sunghoon Kwon, Insong Koh, Seungwoo Hwang, Heung-Woo Park, Hye-Ryun Kang, Ju Han Kim, Miyoung Kim and Dong Soon Lee *Blood* 2016
- Clonal Changes Detected By Target Capture Sequencing and Molecular Cytogenetic Study in Patients with Aplastic Anemia. Heesue Park, <u>Heewon Seo</u>, Si Nae Park, Kyoungok Im, Jung Ah Kim, Sang Mee Hwang, Ju Han Kim and Dong Soon Lee *Blood* 2015

### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

- Rare and Common Disease Variant Analysis using Next-generation Sequence
  The 12th Genome Data Analysis (GDA) Workshop, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea
- Exome Sequencing Analysis in Clinical Research Feb 2014 Feb 2017
  From 6th to 12th Genome Data Analysis (GDA) Workshop, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea
- NGS Platforms and Applications

  Aug 2013 Feb 2017

  From 5th to 12th Genome Data Analysis (GDA) Workshop, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea
- Advanced Methods and Algorithms for Genetic and Genomic data Analysis
   Aug 2016

   The 11th Genome Data Analysis (GDA) Workshop, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea
- Advanced R Graphics
   Mar 2013 Mar 2016
   From 5th to 12th R for Bioinformatics and Biomedicine Workshop, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea
- The 1000 Genomes Project and Human Genome Diversity Feb 2015 Feb 2016 From 8th to 10th Genome Data Analysis (GDA) Workshop, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea

101 College Street, PMCRT 11-410 • Toronto, ON M5G 1L7 (416) 879-6775 • Heewon.Seo@lootpiz.com

## **TEACHING EXPERIENCE (Cont'd)**

• RNA-Seq Expression Profile Analysis

Aug 2012 - Feb 2016

From 3rd to 10th Genome Data Analysis (GDA) Workshop, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea

• Introduction to Linux for Genome Data Analysis

May 2014 - Nov 2014

Course: Certified Scientist in BioMedical Informatics (CSBMI), Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea

### **SOFTWARE**

- **SYNERGxDB** (http://SYNERGxDB.ca/) is a web-based database that provides the largest integrated database in drug combination screenings and molecular profiles to discover effective combinations and predictive biomarkers.
- CaReAI [kæri:el] (Capturing Read Alignments, https://github.com/lootpiz/CaReAI) is a high-performance alignment capturing tool for visualizing the read-alignment status of nucleotide sequences and obtaining read-level data for evaluating variant calls and detecting technical biases.
- VVA (Variant Visualization and Annotation, https://github.com/lootpiz/VVA) is a gene- and variant-centred visualization tool to be used for exome sequencing data analysis and is optimized for displaying the overall distribution of variants in a gene at a glance.
- KRDK (Korean Rare Disease Knowledge base, http://www.snubi.org/software/raredisease/) is a
  web-based, research oriented data repository that provides comprehensive information for rare
  disease research: disease review, clinics, directory, mutation database, patient registry, and
  biobank.

### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE SKILLS

- High-level languages: C/C++
- Scripting languages: R, Python, HTML, PHP, and javascript (Node)
- Structured query languages (SQL): MySQL, MariaDB, and MongoDB (NoSQL)

### **REFERENCES**

Benjamin Haibe-Kains, PhD, benjamin.haibe.kains@utoronto.ca
 Senior Scientist,
 Princess Margaret Cancer Centre, University Health Network, Toronto, Canada

Ju Han Kim, MD, PhD, MS, juhan@snu.ac.kr
 Chair and Professor, Div. of Biomedical Informatics,
 Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea